# Edward Bryant

Chicago, Illinois 312.315.7625 hello@edwardbryant.com

portfolio: http://www.edwardbryant.com/portfolio.html linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/pub/edward-bryant/8/791/594 github: https://github.com/edwardbryant

I am a full stack web developer who is currently focused on JavaScript and Python. After law school and several years working in the legal and tax industry, where my role partially included web development, I am looking to transition into a full-time developer role where I can further improve my skills. I have had experience with both frontend and backend technologies. I am passionate about web accessibility, open source software, and natural language processing.

### **SKILLS**

HTML5 · microdata · CSS3 · SASS · JavaScript · jQuery · Python · PHP · MySQL · git · Bootstrap 2/3 · PostgreSQL · SQLAlchemy · Flask · responsive design · NLTK 3 · SQLite · PostgreSQL · Underscore.js · MVC · object-oriented programming · Vagrant · Agile development

### **EXPERIENCE**

## Analyst, Wolters Kluwer (Riverwoods, IL) · Jul 2001–Mar 2015

I designed and developed 20+ web apps related to state tax (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Underscore.js, Knockout.js). I proposed and communicated business requirements to developers for internal editorial software (e.g., web monitoring), according to agile development methods. I served on company-wide committee to establish new XML DTD standards for all content in North American market. I created content for marketing and corporate communications departments (blog posts, social media, etc.). I provided analysis and content on judicial, legislative, and regulatory actions at the state and federal level.

Database Developer, Golphus.com/PressFactory (Chicago, IL) · Jan 2011–Nov 2013

As a freelancer, I designed and implemented a MySQL database (approx. 100M) for tracking over 18,000 golf courses, as well as users, scores, and handicapping data. I aided in the creation of backend code for querying and updating database. I provided

post-launch database support, including modifying tables, monitoring traffic, and importing data.

Database Dev./Attorney (Contract), Aspect (San Jose, CA) · Nov 2000–Jun 2001

In a temporary project-based position, I reviewed sales contracts and compiled data on contract versioning, common provisions, and custom amendments. I also made recommendations for database table structures that aligned with that data and created accompanying documentation.

Attorney (Contract), Thelen, Reid, & Priest (San Jose, CA) · Jul 2000–Nov 2000

Attorney (Contract), Wilson Sonsini Goodrich & Rosati (Palo Alto, CA) · Jan 2000–May 2000

Attorney (Contract), Finnegan, Henderson, Farabow, Garett & Dunner LLP (Palo Alto, CA) · Sep 1999–Dec 1999

### **EDUCATION**

Udacity, Inc. — Full Stack Nanodegree Program, Feb 2015 – current
Thinkful, Inc. — Frontend Developer Mentor Program, 2015
IIT, Chicago-Kent College of Law, Chicago, IL — J.D. (Cert. IP), 1999
Bradley University, Peoria, IL — B.S. (Political Science), 1996

### **AWARDS**

Winner LexPredict Challenge, LexHacks hackathon, Jun 2015